Shayan Abedi

Richmond Hill, ON L3T 7T7

Email: <a href="mailto:shayanabedi.dev@gmail.com/in/shayanabedi.dev@gmail.

GitHub: https://github.com/ShayanAbedi
Portfolio: https://shayanabedi.com

Profile

I am currently employed as a Frontend Developer at Passiv. My career goals are to acquire knowledge and obtain work experience in the IT industry as well as becoming an integral part of a successful company.

Skills

Front-end Back-end Source control
JavaScript | Typescript | React Node.js | Python Git (GitHub, GitLab)

Redux | HTML | CSS REST | SQL

Work Experience

Passiv Inc. | Software Developer

10/2020 – Present | Remote (Fredericton, New Brunswick)

- Worked with the UX/UI design team to improve the existing user onboarding process and decrease user churn rate by 20%.
- Developed in-app tours with React for all the features, reducing support tickets.
- Implemented an email verification system for the app, increasing the privacy of the app.
- Created a Node SDK for customers to get started with the REST API.

University of New Brunswick (CHAIN group) | Software Developer

10/2019 – 08/2020 | Fredericton, New Brunswick

- Developed web pages based on provided mockups, utilizing JavaScript, Node.js, React, HTML, and CSS.
- Designed and implemented RESTful APIs.
- Implemented authentication using the Passport JS library.
- Resolved known technical shortcomings and bugs on both the front-end and back-end.

Medavie Blue Cross | Computer Science Co-op student

05/2019 – 08/2019 | Moncton, New Brunswick

- Implemented an automated system for the data quality validation process using Oracle SOL, Python, and Alteryx.
- Structured the project from requirements gathering to the deployment of the system.
- Since August 2019, the designed system is being used by the QA team in order to reduce hours of manual procedures.

UNB Persia Associations (Cultural Club) | Public Relations Officer

10/2015 – 10/2016 | Fredericton, New Brunswick | Volunteer

- Worked within a team of executive members in order to arrange various university and community events.
- Maintained an active presence on UNB Persia's social media by promoting the club's meetings and events, which resulted in an increase in club membership, visibility, and event attendance.

Education

University of New Brunswick | Bachelor of Computer Science

09/2015 - 08/2020: Fredericton, New Brunswick

Personal Projects

Covid-19 Tracker

https://covidtracker.shayanabedi.com

Created a website using React (Hooks and Context API) and a 3rd party web API, which enables viewers to see the most current reports of Covid-19 cases in every country and within Canadian provinces.